“Episode 22”
《第22集》
Madam Hua, why did you think of coming to me today?
华夫人， 你今天怎么想到来找我的？
I keep the advice Meng's mother thought about it.
我保留了孟妈妈想了想的建议。
I don't think this is a bad idea.
我不认为这是一个坏主意。
Today we are here to discuss the details.
今天我们在这里讨论细节。
I already know that Nong Hua is a smart person.
我已经知道 农华是个聪明人了。
I just don't know anything.
我只是什么都不知道。
Introduction to the Bell Family Garden
贝尔家族花园简介
Even if you want to help Madam Meng.
就算你想帮助孟夫人。
You probably won't be able to do much.
你可能无能为力。
I have been here for many years.
我已经在这里很多年了。
If you have any questions, you can come and ask.
如果您有什么疑问， 可以过来询问。
if we work together
如果我们一起工作
I will definitely tell you everything.
我一定会告诉你一切。
Then
然后
Do you know what your boss likes?
你知道你的老板喜欢什么吗？
You asked the right person.
你问对人了。
My brother likes sweets.
我弟弟喜欢吃甜食。
if you please him
如果你取悦他
You can never make a mistake.
你永远不会犯错误。
dessert? But there are too many.
甜点？ 但数量太多了。
Did you forget?
你忘了吗？
the former princess
前公主
What did he ask you to send him?
他让你送什么给他？
This time it's not the real Richie's face.
这次 不是真正的里奇的脸。
Instead, they sent a lich to Huang Cheng.
而是派了一个巫妖给黄成。
It is not suffering.
这不是痛苦。
Tai Hao showed mercy to the princess.
太浩对公主发了慈悲。
Where are the difficulties?
困难在哪里？
Yeah, where am I?
是啊，我在哪儿？
I like Richie because of his grandson .
我喜欢里奇是因为他的孙子。
Lychees are my sister's favorite food.
荔枝是我姐姐最喜欢的食物。
Therefore, lychee honey...
因此，荔枝蜜...
Your Majesty has been an expressionless person since ancient times .
陛下自古以来就是一个面无表情的人。
I just found out about this.
我刚刚知道这件事。
Been here for quite some time
在这里已经有一段时间了
You must never tell anyone.
你绝对不能告诉任何人。
I see my master, treat you differently.
我见我师父， 对你不一样了。
someday if you come to stay
有一天 如果你来留下来
In the garden of the head family like me
像我一样在一家人的花园里
don't forget me
不要忘记我
Do you know your manners?
你知道自己的礼仪吗？
Why are you in such a hurry?
你为什么这么急？
Your Majesty has just had a meeting. After all the deacons are done
陛下刚刚开完会。 当所有执事完成后
Leave first and then come back.
先离开，然后再回来。
But His Majesty ordered so. When Lady Hua comes to Zhong Family Garden
但陛下却如此吩咐。 当华夫人来到钟家花园时
You must report it immediately.
您必须立即报告。
- Has she arrived? - please.
- 她到了吗？ - 请。
Now, she please go to Mother Meng’s house.
现在， 请她去孟妈妈家一趟。
I salute you
我向你们致敬
Sir, we just had a meeting.
先生，我们刚刚开会。
Are the Butlers finished?
管家完结了吗？
Yes, I came to see Hua Chen.
是的，我是来看华晨的。
Because I have something important to say.
因为我有重要的事情要说。
You came at just the right time.
你来得正是时候。
Me and enrichment
我与充实
I just finished a call.
我刚刚打完电话。
Why did you visit recently?
您最近为何来访？
Meng Yifei often
孟一飞经常
It seems my master doesn't want me.
看来我的主人不想要我了。
He is very close to Meng Yifei.
他和孟一飞的关系很亲密。
This is my second time. you interrupted us
这是我第二次。 你打断了我们
why?
为什么？
It's been some time since you've been here. If you don't come to mom
你来这儿已经有一段时间了。 如果你不来找妈妈
I came to see Maeng Yeobi.
我是来看Maeng Yeobi的。
Not so much for my mother.
对于我的母亲来说则不然。
But why did Meng Yifei meet you?
可是孟一飞为什么会遇见你呢？
more often than me
比我更频繁
How about bringing a bodyguard today?
今天带个保镖怎么样？
Come to Zhong Family Garden.
来到钟家花园。
I just stopped by Jongga Garden.
我刚刚路过宗家花园。
You don't need many servants.
你不需要很多仆人。
Is that so?
是这样吗？
I heard it at this time, you and that guard
我这个时候听到了， 你和那个守卫
very close
很接近
It was the same last time. Knowing that you are injured
上次也是这样。 知道你受伤了
You left me in a hurry.
你匆匆离开了我。
I thought it was for you.
我以为这是给你的。
He was no longer just a bodyguard.
他不再只是一个保镖。
Hua Rong Zhou is my bodyguard.
周华蓉是我的保镖。
He is faithful to me.
他对我很忠诚。
And that person was hurt because of me.
而那个人因为我而受到伤害。
Of course I worry about him.
我当然担心他。
Are you just a bodyguard?
你只是一个保镖吗？
Do you like lychee honey?
你喜欢荔枝蜜吗？
Are you asking about my tastes?
你是在问我的口味吗？
Few people know about this.
很少有人知道这一点。
Even though I like sweets
虽然我很喜欢甜食
But I can't eat honey.
但我不能吃蜂蜜。
I once ate it by accident when I was young.
小时候有一次不小心吃到了。
And I almost died
而我差点就死了
The doctor said I was allergic to honey.
医生说我对蜂蜜过敏。
This is a matter of my safety.
这事关我的安全。
I'm afraid that someone will secretly attack me.
我害怕有人会暗中攻击我。
So my mother took care of all the servants.
所以我母亲照顾所有的仆人。
Who already knows all about this?
谁已经知道这一切了？
But I can tell you.
但我可以告诉你。
You don't tell anyone else.
你不告诉其他人。
Actually, there is something like that.
事实上，确实有这样的事情。
The next day, if there's anything you want to know
第二天如果有什么想知道的
You can ask me directly.
你可以直接问我。
Can you tell me everything?
你能告诉我一切吗？
And what about the assassin who killed my brother?
那么杀死我兄弟的刺客呢？
Have you found him yet?
你找到他了吗？
Ahian
阿希安
I will handle this matter.
我会处理这件事。
I promise , I won't let the mastermind go.
我保证 ，我不会放过主谋的。
I don't want you to be this tired.
我不想让你这么累。
Leave it to me.
交给我。
You don't need to do anything.
你不需要做任何事情。
but
但
If I knew who the main character was
如果我知道主角是谁
I will handle this matter myself.
这件事我自己来处理。
Please do whatever you want.
请做任何你想做的事。
Roasted Chestnuts Fresh and fragrant chestnuts.
烤栗子 栗子 新鲜、香浓。
Freshly roasted chestnuts.
刚烤好的栗子。
You can stop by first to see and taste it.
你可以先停下来看看、尝尝。
roasted chestnuts
烤栗子
- Would you like some roasted chestnuts? - Yes, please.
- 你想要一些烤栗子吗？ - 是的，请。
Stop by and take a look first. Roasted chestnuts.
先停下来看看。烤栗子。
Big, fragrant roasted chestnuts.
烤栗子又大又香。
Madam, would you like some roasted chestnuts?
女士， 您要吃烤栗子吗？
I took out a bag of roasted chestnuts.
我拿出一袋烤栗子。
yes
是的
- here
- 这里
Thank you very much
非常感谢
I am giving everything to you.
我把一切都给你。
roasted chestnuts
烤栗子
You can come and taste it first.
你可以先来尝尝。
freshly baked
新鲜出炉的
Sweet and fragrant roasted chestnuts.
烤栗子又甜又香。
Please come.
请过来。
so sweet
如此甜蜜
-Why aren't you eating? - Akian
-你为什么不吃饭？ -阿基安
It's you, the murderer.
是你，凶手。
It was really you, you murderous bastard.
真的是你 这个杀人不眨眼的混蛋。
I never dreamed I would meet you here.
我做梦也没想到会在这里遇见你。
Heaven really does have eyes.
天果然有眼。
Heaven has pity on my father-in-law.
老天爷怜悯我的岳父。
thank heaven
谢天谢地
Whoa, let’s talk nicely.
呵呵，我们好好谈谈吧。
He is my bodyguard.
他是我的保镖。
If you slander an innocent person
如果你诽谤无辜的人
You can notify the authorities.
您可以通知当局。
Let them hold you.
让他们抱着你。
- You... - Like this in front of heaven and earth
- 你... - 就这样在天地面前
Why would I slander him?
我为什么要诽谤他？
If it's not true
如果这不是真的
Baby, look.
宝贝，看。
Is this the bastard?
这就是混蛋吗？
It killed your father.
它杀了你父亲。
Even if he turns to ashes, I remember him.
即使他化为灰烬， 我也记得他。
That's right, that person killed my father.
没错，就是那个人杀了我的父亲。
A murderer, he is a murderer.
杀人犯，他就是杀人犯。
Folks, he is a murderer.
各位，他是杀人犯。
I am Hwari’s daughter-in-law.
我是华里的儿媳妇。
Wealthy merchants of border towns
边陲小镇的富商
At that time, my father-in-law felt sorry for this guy.
当时我的岳父 就觉得对不起这个家伙。
So I bought it to become a servant.
所以我买了它来当仆人。
But this damn kid took advantage. stab us in the back
但这个该死的小子却利用了这一点。 在背后捅我们一刀
I killed my father-in-law and then stole his money.
我杀了我的岳父 ，然后偷了钱。
Then I ran away
然后我就逃跑了
This issue has been over for 7 years now.
这个问题已经结束7年了。
Fortunately, heaven still has mercy.
幸好老天爷还是有怜悯的。
Let's meet him here.
我们在这里见见他吧。
Everyone
每个人
Hurry up and report it to the authorities.
赶紧向有关部门举报吧。
Please arrest him.
请逮捕他。
catch him
抓住他
He just said it himself. 7 years have passed
只是他自己说的。 7年过去了
You may remember people incorrectly.
你可能会记错人。
There is no evidence.
没有证据。
Then come and sue. Are you such an innocent person?
那你就来告吧， 你就是这么无辜的人吗？
Am I remembering the wrong person?
我是不是记错人了？
his evil face
他邪恶的脸
I can't remember wrong.
我没记错。
At that time we saw that he looked good. So I bought him.
当时我们就看到他长得不错。 所以我买了他。
But unfortunately we don't think so.
但不幸的是我们不这么认为。
We will bring war to our home.
我们会将战争带入我们的家园。
the most beautiful person in this world
这个世界上最美丽的人
He's not the only one.
他不是唯一一个。
Mother, you are so kind.
妈妈，您真善良。
I was fooled by this evil man.
我被这个邪恶的人愚弄了。
Do not worry. I am here.
不用担心。我在这里。
I will not allow them to slander you.
我不会允许他们诽谤你。
This is not a slander.
这不是诽谤。
to let go
放手
I once said that I killed someone.
我曾经说过我杀了一个人。
owner...
所有者...
Did everyone hear what he said?
大家都听到他说的话了吗？
Did you hear that?
你听到了吗？
He confessed to the murder.
他承认了谋杀罪。
- Tell the authorities to arrest him. - How bold!
- 告诉当局逮捕他。 - 多么大胆啊！
Do you think you're going to arrest my people? Can you do whatever you want?
你认为你要逮捕我的人吗？ 你可以为所欲为吗？
You are protecting a murderer.
你正在保护一个杀人犯。
Hope has arrived.
希望已经到来。
- Please move out - I'm waiting.
- 请搬出去 - 我在等。
You are in awe.
你很敬畏。
Sir, please restore justice to us.
先生， 请还我们正义。
That guy killed my father-in-law.
那家伙杀了我的岳父。
Hurry and catch him before he runs away .
赶紧在他逃跑之前抓住他 。
I am Hwari’s daughter-in-law.
我是华里的儿媳妇。
Wealthy merchants from border towns
边陲小镇的富商
His father-in-law takes pity on him.
他的岳父很同情他。
So he took him in as a servant.
于是收他为奴。
But this murderer should take his chance while we are gone.
但这个凶手 应该趁我们不在的时候抓住机会。
I killed my father-in-law
我杀了我的岳父
Then he ran away with the money.
然后他就带着钱跑了。
He has been doing this for 7 years.
他这样做已经7年了。
Sir, this is all true.
先生，这 都是真的。
Sir, please restore justice to us.
先生， 请还我们正义。
Let's stop coming together apart from each other.
让我们别再分开聚在一起了。
cystic mother
囊性母亲
This woman blocked my path. complain about her own dissatisfaction
这个女人挡住了我的去路。 抱怨某人的不满
- You can go. - I can't ignore him.
- 你可以走了 - 我不能忽视他
Ms. Hua, please make way.
华小姐，请让路。
We'll take him back and interrogate him.
我们会带他回去审问他。
This issue happened very briefly.
这个问题发生的时间非常短暂。
Your Majesty has already arrived here.
陛下已经到了这里。
It seemed like all of Huang Cheng's events.
这似乎就是黄成的全部事情了。
You won't be able to escape your gaze.
你将无法逃脱你的目光。
we should admire
我们应该敬佩
Your work is really fast.
你的工作速度真快。
I happened to pass by.
我正好路过。
And then I heard there was a murder
然后我听说发生了一起谋杀案
So I hurriedly came here.
于是我就赶紧来到了这里。
Mother Nang Hua also helped with cooperation.
妈妈囊花也帮忙配合。
cooperate or
合作或
Someone is slandering me.
有人在诽谤我。
Fahrenheit people
华氏人
What you mean is, I will stand and watch you.
你的意思是， 我会站着看着你。
Do you just take me like that?
你就这么对待我吗？
It's not like that.
不像那样。
Mr. Hua, you need to investigate clearly first.
华先生， 你得先调查清楚。
so that we can decide this case
以便我们可以决定这个案子
When investigation is necessary
当需要调查时
If so, please complete your research.
如果是这样，请完成您的研究。
Then come and arrest him.
那就过来逮捕他吧。
Just a few words and you will get him there.
只要几句话， 你就能把他带到那里。
Or are you afraid of that?
或者你害怕这个吗？
The Hu family will cover up his crime for him.
胡家将为他掩盖罪行。
And help him escape
并帮助他逃脱
Chen Yuan has a truly beautiful face.
陈媛 有着一张真正美丽的脸。
Ahian
阿希安
Come here, Achen.
过来吧，亚琛。
Someone is trying to defame me. I don't.
有人试图诽谤我。 我不。
Do you really know the man next to you well?
你真的很了解你身边的这个人吗？
Obey me and follow me.
服从我并跟随我。
Hua Rongzhou was framed.
华容舟被陷害。
Slur or not, he didn't even use the last name Hua.
不管有没有诽谤 ，他甚至没有使用华这个姓氏。
Huarongzhou
华容洲
There are too many people here.
这里的人太多了。
Come with me. Let me tell you.
跟我来。让我告诉你。
I'm worried about the king. What should Huarongzhou do?
我为大王担心， 华容州该怎么办？
I don't want to listen to you.
我不想听你的。
Talk about what worries you about that person again.
再次谈论那个人让你担心的事情。
- Your Majesty, - this is my guard captain.
- 陛下， - 这是我的侍卫队长。
Linjiang
临江
He usually works in the shadows.
他通常在暗处工作。
Take your time, girl.
慢慢来，女孩。
Miss , my brother was rude to you.
小姐 ，我哥哥对你很粗鲁。
I have to apologize on his behalf.
我必须代表他向他道歉。
You still have one more brother, right?
你还有一个弟弟，对吧？
Mr. Crosstalk, do you mean 1,000 yuan?
相声先生， 您是说1000元吗？
You've met him before.
你以前见过他。
He is my subordinate.
他是我的下属。
Ahian
阿希安
At the teahouse that day
那天在茶馆
I didn't mean to insult you.
我并不是有意侮辱你。
I saw your brother causing trouble.
我看见你哥哥惹麻烦了。
So I gave it to them. Help the woman play the cliff ghost.
所以我把它给了他们。 帮助女人扮演悬崖鬼。
I never thought I'd drag you into something like this.
我从来没想过我会把你拖进这种事里。
What do you want to say? Introduction to Huarongzhou
你想说什么？ 华容洲简介
If you have already looked at these documents.
如果您已经看过这些文档。
You will understand.
你会明白的。
This document has the name "Qi Rongzhou".
这份文件的名字是“齐荣舟”。
It was Huarongzhou. That's what works next to you
那是华容洲。 这就是你身边的工作
His original surname was Qi.
他原姓齐。
My hometown is Hoeyang County.
我的家乡是濮阳县。
It's about 1000 miles from here.
距离这里大约有1000英里。
Ahian
阿希安
I don't think you know this.
我认为你不知道这一点。
You didn't check my history.
你没有检查我的历史。
People around you, right?
你身边的人，对吗？
I had never seen him before.
我以前从未见过他。
At the moon festival party
中秋联欢会上
That person suddenly stood in front of you
那个人突然 站在你面前
I felt he had a familiar face.
我 感觉他有一张熟悉的面孔。
He is a roadside beggar.
他是一个路边乞丐。
And the waiter at the teahouse you met once
还有你曾经见过的茶馆服务员
You could tell he was approaching you intentionally. with hidden intentions
你可以看出他是故意接近你的。 带着隐藏的意图
So they sent someone to investigate him.
于是他们就派人去调查他。
Have you ever met him? How can you become a roadside beggar?
你见过他吗？ 怎么会沦为路边乞丐呢？
I just ran into him.
我刚刚碰到了他。
hit the tank
击中坦克
Is there such a coincidence?
有这样的巧合吗？
Now we have your bodyguards here.
现在我们 有你的保镖了。
Someone I know.
我认识的一个人。
Hualongzhou was not that kind of person.
化龙洲不是那样的人。
Khun Nuwa
坤女娲
Although Qi Rongzhou
虽然齐容舟
He would not kill King Li for money.
他不会为了钱而杀厉王。
But he killed people several times.
但他却多次杀过人。
Have you ever heard the story?
你听过这个故事吗？
Is this Weishen craftsman?
这就是威神工匠吗？
Did you know that it is an artisan shop? Where is the best place here?
你知道这是一家手工艺品店吗？ 这里最好的地方是哪里？
i heard it
我听说了
Once upon a time, there was a female craftsman named Wi-Hyeon (魏熙).
从前，有一位女工匠，名叫魏熙。
Your skills are top notch.
你的技能是一流的。
Female craftsman or why have I never heard of her?
女工匠不然 我怎么没听说过她？
All women admired her.
所有的女人都钦佩她。
I'm sorry to hear that she passed away not long ago.
听说她不久前去世了，我感到很遗憾。
I'm somewhat familiar with it.
我对它有些熟悉。
Outskirts of Hwangcheong-gu
黄清区近郊
She is the best craftsman.
她是最好的工匠。
Everyone knows her.
每个人都认识她。
But she was murdered a year ago.
但她一年前被谋杀了。
At first, most people thought:
一开始，大多数人认为：
It was another revenge murder case.
这又是一起复仇杀人案。
When subordinates are investigating
当下属调查时
The story of Qi Rongzhou
齐容舟的故事
They found Wei Xian by chance.
他们偶然发现了魏贤。
Once upon a time, there was a disciple named Yong Zhou.
从前，有一个弟子，名叫永州。
the night before she died
她去世前一天晚上
Someone saw Qi Rongzhou.
有人看到了齐容舟。
But after that there was no sign to continue.
但此后 就没有继续的迹象了。
So this problem is gone.
所以这个问题就没有了。
I give you this bracelet. to protect yourself
我给你这个手镯。 保护自己
Don't commit suicide
不要自杀
Ahian
阿希安
Qi Rongzhou hid a mysterious identity.
齐容舟隐藏着一个神秘的身份。
If Cheonwon didn't know that fact
如果Cheonwon不知道这个事实的话
The Li family secretly spied on him.
李家暗中监视他。
We probably won't find it.
我们可能找不到它。
his past
他的过去
when he was ten years old
当他十岁的时候
He killed and robbed people.
他杀人、抢劫。
Later he killed his teacher.
后来他杀了他的老师。
Oh Qian, I know you are a soft-hearted and pitiful person.
哦，钱， 我知道你是一个心软又可怜的人。
But I will tolerate such dangerous people.
但我会容忍这种危险的人。
How can I be near you?
我怎样才能靠近你？
A couple I met on the street earlier
之前在街上遇到的一对情侣
Is this your work?
这是你的工作吗？
I do it because I have good intentions for you.
我这样做是因为我对你有好意。
I'm afraid you won't believe me.
恐怕你不会相信我。
So I told Chen Yuan. bring it here
于是我就告诉了陈源。 把它带到这里
But it was he who set it up.
但这是他安排的。
Performance on the road itself
道路本身的性能
I am afraid if Qi Rongzhou is exposed.
只怕齐容舟暴露了。
He will get angry and hurt you.
他会生气并伤害你。
I am here to protect you.
我来这里是为了保护你。
Are you afraid that I won't trust you?
你是怕我不信任你吗？
Your Majesty, come here.
陛下，请过来。
Because they were afraid of Huarongzhou.
因为他们害怕华容洲。
Will it really hurt me?
真的会伤害我吗？
If not, what is?
如果不是，那是什么？
Or do you think I miss you?
或者你觉得我想念你吗？
Does the truth not care and protects him?
难道真相不关心、保护他吗？
thank you
谢谢
If you don't have enough bodyguards
如果你没有足够的保镖
You will choose Chen Yuan. Or Linjiang.
你会选择陈远。 或者临江。
They typically work in the shadows.
他们通常在暗处工作。
The strategy was great.
这个策略很棒。
No worse than anyone else.
不比任何人差。
They are our Lord's people.
他们是我们主的子民。
I wouldn't dare.
我不敢。
i gave it to you
我把它给你了
will be your person
将成为你的人
Thank you for your generosity.
感谢您的慷慨。
But today's problems are more than I can handle.
但今天的问题超出了我的处理能力。
Sir, please give me some time.
先生，请给我一些时间。
So let's talk more.
所以让我们多谈谈吧。
underfoot
脚下
When Khun Chai Yai's bodyguards are nearby.
当Khun Chai Yai 的保镖 在附近时。
are you okay
你还好吗
Qian Er
千儿
Is something wrong?
有什么问题吗？
I'm doing great.
我很好。
I'm really worried.
我真的很担心。
When I heard this news
当我听到这个消息时
I am very worried.
我非常担心。
Until I almost went out to look for you.
直到我差点出去找你。
I was later told that there was hope.
后来我被告知还有希望。
Have someone send you back.
请人送你回去。
you...
你...
I'm sorry for making you worry father.
对不起，爸爸，让您担心了。
Qian’er, do you remember?
千儿，你还记得吗？
Next it's time to choose a servant.
接下来是选择仆人的时候了。
Great care must be taken.
必须非常小心。
People who don't know how to sleep.
不知道如何睡觉的人。
I will not allow you to take it back and use it.
我不会允许你 收回并使用它。
especially...
尤其...
Especially the people you brought with you.
尤其是你带来的人。
Zhong Family Mansion
钟家大宅
I think so.
我想是这样。
I recommend double checking their history .
我建议仔细检查他们的历史记录 。
Not just a servant
不仅仅是一个仆人
What do you say?
你怎么说？
No, teacher, I'm just a little tired.
不，老师， 我只是有点累了。
I don't care about you at all.
我根本不关心你。
I just went through something scary.
我刚刚经历了一些可怕的事情。
You need to get complete rest.
你需要得到充分的休息。
Get some rest, honey.
好好休息吧，亲爱的。
You guys take good care of me.
你们好好照顾我。
All right.
好的。
to let go
放手
Please help Guard Hua .
请帮助华护卫 。
He could never be a murderer. as they accused
他永远不可能成为杀人犯。 正如他们指责的那样
That person must have been framed.
那人一定是被陷害了。
Please help him.
请帮助他。
Choi Joo, please leave me alone for a moment.
崔珠， 请让我安静一会儿。
Miss, please.
小姐，请。
- You can go. - Miss, please.
- 你可以走了 - 小姐，请吧
- Let's go - Miss, please help him.
- 我们走吧 - 小姐，请帮助他。
to let go
放手
For now, send someone to deliver Mu Yao’s letter.
现在先 派人去送慕瑶的信吧。
to let go
放手
Very funny.
很搞笑。
It's really ridiculous.
实在是太可笑了。
Please tell us.
请告诉我们。
Why did everything come together?
为什么一切都 聚集在一起？
Miss, what are you going to do?
小姐，你要做什么？
Tonight you drove out the slaves. Located in the firewood warehouse
今晚你赶走了奴隶。 位于柴火仓库内
go away.
离开。
Capturing him would be a waste of the Hua family's rice and fish.
抓了他 ，就浪费了华家的鱼米。
All right.
好的。
I think you decided to be a coward.
我认为你决定成为一个胆小鬼。
And as if you don't know, here I am again.
就好像你不知道一样， 我又来了。
Qian’er decided to let you go.
倩儿决定放你走。
I'm curious.
我很好奇。
Why did Hwacheon do that? To have the courage to be so reckless?
华川为什么要这么做？ 有胆量如此鲁莽？
In fact, he was planning to attack me.
事实上，他是打算攻击我。
It's behind this.
原来是在这背后
Qian’er didn’t know.
倩儿不知道。
I am the one who came to set you free.
我是来让你自由的人。
She is actually a gentle person.
她其实是一个温柔的人。
Cowardly since ancient times
自古懦弱
Originally, she shouldn't have gotten involved in this matter.
本来，她就不该插手这件事情。
You must remember this after I release you .
我放了你之后， 你一定要记住这一点。
Things not to say
不该说的话
It must be kept for life.
它必须终生保存。
Is she really a gentle person?
她真的是一个温柔的人吗？
Is she a coward?
她是个胆小鬼吗？
Is your eyesight weird or something?
你的视力是不是有点奇怪啊？
I know my daughter well.
我很了解我的女儿。
I have set you free.
我已经让你自由了。
Why don't you hurry and escape? Why did you come here?
你为什么不赶紧逃走呢？ 你为什么来这里？
plural?
复数？
what happened at the party
聚会上发生了什么
I was careless.
我粗心。
make someone take advantage
使某人利用
Even family members were caught in the crossfire.
就连家人也 被卷入了交火之中。
So you came to apologize?
所以你是来道歉的？
You think my sister is unhappy.
你以为我姐姐不高兴。
So he was attacked during the chaos?
所以说他是在混乱的时候被袭击的？
It's my fault.
我的错。
I caused your brother's death.
我害死了你哥哥。
And do you know?
你知道吗？
I am the only assassin's target that day .
那天我是唯一的刺客目标。
Hua Shen took the sword for me until I died.
华神一直替我保管这把剑，直到我死去。
I have no idea.
我不知道。
yes
是的
moon festival party
中秋节聚会
Very confusing.
很混乱。
Everyone ran to survive.
每个人都为了生存而奔跑。
Who has time to worry about other people?
谁有时间去担心别人？
Even you, the mastermind
就连你这个主谋
I still don't know this.
我还是不知道这个。
How can other people know?
其他人怎么知道？
I was wrong about this. I have no excuses.
我在这件事上错了。 我没有任何借口。
If you hold a grudge against something
如果你对某事怀恨在心
You can come down to me.
你可以下来找我。
Only
仅有的
Don't get her in trouble again.
别再给她惹麻烦了。
when you don't trust
当你不信任的时候
Then why didn't you take her?
那你为什么不带她走？
Why did you leave her there?
你为什么把她留在那里？
She is the one who decides.
她是做决定的人。
And I respect her decision.
我尊重她的决定。
Do you respect her decision?
你尊重她的决定吗？
Then you kill someone for me.
那你就替我杀一个人吧。
And I will never bother her again.
而且我再也不会打扰她了。
I love you and your father.
我爱你和你的父亲。
It's enough to make your head spin.
这足以让你头晕目眩。
I won't interfere. With your problem
我不会干涉。 与你的问题
Do you know my father?
你认识我父亲吗？
In fact, he didn't tell you. It's the same thing.
事实上，他没有告诉你。 这是同一件事。
About what?
关于什么？
Go ahead and ask them directly.
直接去问他们吧。
“If you look at his expression, it doesn’t seem like he’s lying,” he said.
“如果你看他的表情， 就不会觉得他在撒谎，”他说。
“But in my past life”
“但在我的前世”
“They have never met.”
“他们从未见过面。”
"What happen?"
“发生什么事？”
about your brother
关于你哥哥
i owe you
我欠你
But if you plan to hurt Mu Yao again
但如果你打算再伤害沐瑶
I won't just sit by and watch.
我不会只是袖手旁观。
If Mu Yao causes me trouble, I will say so .
如果慕瑶给我添麻烦，我就直说 。
I will never disturb you again.
我再也不会打扰你了。
But if I cause trouble to Mu Yao
但如果我给慕瑶添麻烦
Could you please contact me?
可以联系我吗？
This they call being alone.
他们 称之为孤独。
Mu Yao will not cause you any more trouble.
慕瑶不会再给你添麻烦了。
No matter how you look at it
不管你怎么看
I feel like I'm at a disadvantage.
我感觉自己处于劣势。
And what do you want?
你想要什么？
remember
记住
You owe me a lot.
你欠我很多。
One day I will go and get it back.
有一天我会去取回它。
Yes, I will wait.
是的，我会等待。
Are you injured?
你受伤了吗？
In the third drawer of the bookshelf
在书架的第三个抽屉里
Contains Jintao powder
含有金桃粉
It helps stop bleeding and relieves pain.
它有助于止血和缓解疼痛。
Go get it yourself.
你自己去拿吧。
Hurry up.
赶快。
I fell in love with you from the moment I first saw you.
从我第一次见到你的那一刻起，我就爱上了你。
So I can't stop thinking about you.
所以我无法停止想你。
Stop using this stick.
别再用这根棍子了。
I'll count to three.
我数到三。
I'm sure I'll cry if I don't go.
我确信如果我不去的话我会哭。
one
一
Are not you curious? Why do I keep bothering you?
你不好奇吗？ 我为什么老是打扰你？
- Two - Someday you will come to me.
- 二 - 有一天你会来找我。
three
三
what's the matter?
怎么了？
sorry.
对不起。
I am the one who should apologize.
我才是最应该道歉的人。
Why are you apologizing?
你为什么道歉？
She was right.
她是对的。
Even though the plan is a secret
尽管计划是秘密
But the results are revealing.
但结果很能说明问题。
There are many stories.
有很多故事。
I will never know you and I will never know.
我永远不会认识你 ，我也永远不会知道。
About what?
关于什么？
Agree
同意
When I first approached you
当我第一次接近你时
Because there is a hidden intention
因为有一个隐藏的意图
But later I thought you were interesting.
但后来我觉得你很有趣。
thinking back,
回想起来，
Actually, I don't like you very much.
其实我不太喜欢你。
Then from now on
那么从现在开始
You don't have to pity me.
你不必可怜我。
Don't look for me.
别找我。
And don't even think about me.
甚至别想我。
"Hua Family House"
《华家大宅》
“Wu Suo was playing around with my father. What exactly does it have to do with it?”
“吴索正在和我父亲玩耍。 到底和这件事有什么关系呢？”
“Why have they never met in the past?”
“为什么他们以前从未见过面？”
“And now I’m not seeing any signs.”
“现在我没有 看到任何迹象。”
Mr. Choi Joo , you cannot come in here.
Choi Joo先生 ，你不能进来。
Mr. Choi Joo, you cannot come in.
崔珠先生，你不能进来。
Choi Joo just woke up. I haven't eaten anything yet.
崔珠刚刚醒来。 我还没吃东西呢。
If anything happens, just wait.
如果有什么事情发生，就等着吧。
- Choi Joo - You guys go out first.
- Choi Joo - 你们先出去。
I know you like Hua Rongzhou.
我知道你喜欢华容舟。
But this issue is complex. you give me...
但这个问题很复杂。 你给我...
No, miss.
不，小姐。
sorry.
对不起。
I made a mistake.
我犯了一个错误。
Lady, please punish me.
小姐，请惩罚我吧。
- There's no need for that... - The guard gets angry...
- 没必要…… - 守卫生气了……
Guard Hua only cares about you.
华护卫 只关心你。
He always was like that.
他一直都是这样。
I noticed it from the beginning.
我从一开始就注意到了。
I was offended.
我很生气。
So I made a lot of mistakes.
所以我犯了很多错误。
things that happened
发生的事情
At Mugosa’s wedding
在穆戈萨的婚礼上
I am the one who told her. Where is Caihua?
我就是告诉她的人。 彩花在哪里？
And I fired all the servants and went out into the backyard.
我解雇了所有仆人 ，走到后院。
Mu's concubine
穆氏小妾
To get a chance to create a scene that defames him.
想要有机会制造一场诽谤他的场面。
And at the moon festival party
还有中秋晚会上
I deliberately blocked Guard Hua.
我故意挡住了华护卫。
The assassin had his chance.
刺客有机可乘。
They knocked him unconscious and took him away.
他们把他打昏并把他带走了。
Because of my own selfishness
因为我自己的自私
I have done many mistakes behind your back.
我在你背后犯了很多错误。
I am a dishonest servant.
我是一个不诚实的仆人。
Will you hit me or punish me?
你会打我还是惩罚我？
I am not against it either.
我也不反对。
But the royal guard said:
但皇家侍卫说道：
Guard Hua values ​​the young woman's life more than his own.
华护卫视 少妇的生命胜过自己的生命。
He risked his life to protect you.
他冒着生命危险来保护你。
countless times
无数次
So it doesn't matter what other people say.
所以别人怎么说并不重要。
He never meant to hurt you.
他从来没有想过要伤害你。
I swear on my life
我以我的生命发誓
How good is that person to me?
那个人对我有多好？
You don't have to tell me.
你不必告诉我。
Miss, please. Don't let him suffer like this.
小姐，请。 不要让他受这样的苦。
wake up
醒来
Lady, please punish me.
小姐，请惩罚我吧。
- Miss - Go to jail with me.
- 小姐 - 和我一起去监狱吧。
Teacher Nu, have you arrived?
努老师，你到了吗？
Don't ask for it.
不要要求它。
I am dirty.
我很脏。
Not dirty
不脏
It's not dirty at all
一点也不脏
Your last name is not Hua, is it?
你不姓华，是吗？
me...
我...
So why do you say your last name is Hua?
那你为什么说你姓华呢？
I don't like my old last name.
我不喜欢我的旧姓氏。
So, I have always lived without a last name.
所以，我一直过着没有姓氏的生活。
until I met you
直到我遇见你
I gave myself this last name.
我给自己起了这个姓氏。
Why don't you like old castles?
你为什么不喜欢古城堡？
Why do you have to kill?
为什么一定要杀人呢？
lee big shot
李大佬
And this bracelet
还有这个手链
Where exactly did you get it?
你到底是从哪里得到的？
Because you already know everything
因为你已经知道一切
Don't ask again.
别再问了。
Because I want to hear it from your mouth.
因为我想从你嘴里听到。
How dare they beat you?
他们怎么敢打你？
to let go
放手
Miss, don't you want to listen to me?
小姐， 你不想听我说吗？
You asked me once
你曾经问过我一次
What I still hate Is there a rich family?
我还讨厌的 是有钱人家吗？
“And now?”
“现在？”
You still hate your rich family.
你还是讨厌你的富家子弟。
Has someone ever done something bad to you?
有人对你做过坏事吗？
No, it's okay.
不，没关系。
why?
为什么？
Because I killed that person.
因为我杀了那个人。
I was born in a village.
我出生在一个村庄。
My father is a rural graduate.
我的父亲是一名农村毕业生。
Ambitious but unable to achieve anything.
胸怀大志 却一事无成。
My mom takes care of everything around the house.
我妈妈负责照顾家里的一切。
when i was five years old
当我五岁的时候
My mother is sick.
我妈妈病了。
Zhou Zhou, take your time.
周周，慢慢来。
Mom, please take some medicine.
妈妈，请吃点药吧。
After that, there is no need to make medicine for your mother.
以后就不用再给你妈配药了。
It's a waste of money. There is no use in eating it.
这是浪费钱。 吃了也没啥用。
There is still a long way to go.
还有很长的路要走。
It will take a lot of money.
这将需要很多钱。
Mother, are you going to leave us?
妈妈， 您要离开我们吗？
Tuberculosis is an infectious disease.
结核病是一种传染病。
Please take your child out.
请带你的孩子出去。
Mother , I don't want to leave you.
妈妈 ，我不想离开你。
I don't want to leave my mother.
我不想离开我的母亲。
Listen to your mom, honey.
听你妈妈的话，亲爱的。
Mother, I don't want that.
妈妈，我不想这样。
I need you, mother.
我需要你，妈妈。
I don't want to leave my mother.
我不想离开我的母亲。
mother
母亲
“After a while, my mother passed away.”
“过了一段时间， 我母亲去世了。”
A few years later, my father
几年后，我的父亲
I got money from my mother.
我从妈妈那里得到了钱。
They even refused to pay for treatment.
他们甚至拒绝支付治疗费用。
Go and marry someone else
去嫁给别人吧
The woman
女人
I have a father and a child.
我有一个父亲和一个孩子。
when i was ten years old
当我十岁的时候
My hometown is experiencing a famine situation.
我的家乡 正在经历饥荒。
She urged my father to sell me.
她怂恿我父亲把我卖掉。
Then she said to me. Because I have good looks
然后她对我说。 因为我有好看的外表
So she decided to sell me.
所以她决定卖掉我。
My younger brother doesn't look good.
我弟弟的脸色不太好。
Even if you sell it, there is no price.
就算卖了，也没有价格。
Thank you father.
谢谢你父亲。
The person who took care of me for 10 years
照顾我10年的人
now
现在
Our father-son relationship is over.
我们的父子关系 结束了。
We will never meet again.
我们再也不会见面了。
From now on
今后
I will be called Rong Zhou.
我就叫周蓉吧。
I dare not use your last name again.
我不敢再用你的姓氏。
henceforth
今后
I hope your father takes good care of himself.
我希望你的父亲能够好好照顾自己。
I don't care why she sold me out on purpose .
我不在乎她为什么故意出卖我。
since my mother passed away
自从我母亲去世后
It's no different wherever I am.
无论我在哪里，情况都没有什么不同。
But that woman
但那个女人
I'm jealous of my father
我嫉妒我的父亲
I often talk about my late mother.
我经常谈论我已故的母亲。
So she sold me
于是她就把我卖了
The infamous King Lee
臭名昭著的李金
famous?
著名的？
"Extra Scenes"
“额外场景”
underfoot
脚下
The man is already in prison.
该男子已经入狱。
But the husband and wife
但夫妻俩
Take your chance to escape the chaos.
抓住机会逃离混乱。
Shall I find it for you?
我给你找一下可以吗？
underfoot
脚下
Are you going back to Zhong Family Garden or not?
你还回钟家花园吗？
Come back.
回来。
Accept it.
接受。
They told me to wait 3 more days.
他们告诉我再等三天。
No interrogations are permitted during these three days. no matter what torture
这三天不准审讯。 无论怎样的折磨
Wait.
等待。
please.
请。
"Hua Family House"
《华家大宅》